<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>roylarsen.xyz</title>
    <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on roylarsen.xyz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:30:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.roylarsen.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>saltstack gitfs</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/gitfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:30:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/gitfs/</guid>
      <description>Saltstack gitfs This is mostly notes for myself, but I wanted to write up an easy reference.
basics This is to get a basic setup with a map from saltenv to git branch.
This requires some basic knowlege of saltstack concepts like pillar, salt environments.
My setup is pretty simplistic, I have two main branches: master and dev. The branches are present in the state and pillar repos. Top files are managed per-repo, per-branch (there are probably better ways of handling it, but this is fine for right now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>devops(-ish)</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 11:17:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/devops/</guid>
      <description>Well, not really. I have a pretty decent idea of what&amp;rsquo;s going on.. Trust me, I&amp;rsquo;ve got this (mostly) I&amp;rsquo;ve also figured out how to do images in Hugo, #dealwtithit
mhqa I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on authoring a tool in python, and that&amp;rsquo;s been fun to work on. It&amp;rsquo;s currently pretty limited in scope, but soon I should be able to start building things out and really start doing some fun Continuous Deployment/Delivery stuff for our QA people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Heartbeat Era</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/mhb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 22:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/mhb/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new job! So, as of 20171009, I&amp;rsquo;m in my last week of work at Hachette Book Group. Next week I start my new role as DevOps Engineer at Mobile Heartbeat!
I&amp;rsquo;m an equal mix of excited, scared, and a little bummed.
 Excited because this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been woring towards for a couple years now (the huge pay bump doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt) Scared because it&amp;rsquo;ll be one of my first more senior roles I&amp;rsquo;ve had Bummed because I&amp;rsquo;m leaving Downtown Boston and I&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving my friends at HBG  This job will be a great platform to really start developing my skills in the DevOps space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>terraform</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 22:47:03 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/terraform/</guid>
      <description>A Poorly Written Intro to Terraform So, I&amp;rsquo;m probably late to this party. Very late.
I still have a lot to play around with, but after creating and destroying some Digital Ocean droplets, I&amp;rsquo;m already starting to see the power and utility of this tool (it&amp;rsquo;s fun when those things are easily seen right away).
I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty firm believer that Hashicorp deserves their reputation in the Devops space. Everyone uses at least some of their tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>proxmox cloud</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/proxmox-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 20:41:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/proxmox-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Proxmox + salt-cloud = &amp;lt;kinda3 So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on getting salt-cloud playing nicely with Proxmox. The biggest issue I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far is within salt-cloud&amp;rsquo;s proxmox driver is more of a limitation within proxmox itself.
Unless you statically assign you IP address, you&amp;rsquo;re not going to see your IP address in the GUI or in the standard salt-cloud query to your hypervisor. The proxmox driver also allows your to query DNS for the IP address of your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>certificates</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 23:07:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/certificates/</guid>
      <description>Running a certificate authority is kinda annoying I recently had a developer come to me with a question about an error they were getting with the Requests Python Module.
The default for this module is to validate SSL certs. Makes sense, right? Validating SSL should be a thing you should do with HTTPS (you ARE using HTTPS for things, right?)
The issue came up where in development, the dev set validate to false so they could test hitting an API endpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>christmas</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 11:17:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/christmas/</guid>
      <description>christmas. It&amp;rsquo;s December 17th. In a month and a half, I&amp;rsquo;ll have lived in the Boston area for a year.
What. I have one week left of work this year, then HBG is off for Christmas week.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on coming up with my projects for the week so I don&amp;rsquo;t get bored.
## hypervisor.
(proxmox and plex are now things in my env) I want to rebuild my lab Hypervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 17:49:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to make another attempt at starting a personal site/blog.
We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 16:04:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>info@roylarsen.xyz (Roy Larsen)</author>
      <guid>http://www.roylarsen.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey. I&amp;rsquo;m not super great with writing about myself, it aways feels weird. So, who am I?
basics. As of my writing of this, I&amp;rsquo;m 31 years old and living in the Greater Boston Area.
professional. I&amp;rsquo;m currently a DevOps Engineer with Mobile Heartbeat, formally Infrastucture Engineer at Hachette Book Group, formally formally IT Specialist III at State of Vermont I&amp;rsquo;m just figuring this out. My main tasks will be automating our software deployments to client sites.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>